to determine what the code we've been
given will print
we need to understand how the keyword
return
works on line six we call put s
and pass in the return value of invoking
the meal method
looking at the meal method definition
we can see that the last line in the
method is the string dinner
so you may think that the return value
of the meal method
is the string dinner however
remember that the return value
of a ruby method is the evaluated result
of the last line executed
in this case the last line executed will
be line two
and that's because return exits the
method
so ruby will evaluate line two of the
meal method
and when return is executed ruby will
exit the meal method
so line three where you see the string
dinner
will never be processed by ruby when
we're invoking the meal method
because we use return on line two
we know that the return value of
invoking meal
will be the string breakfast and that's
what we can
expect to see output when we call put s
on line six
to see this let's run our code
and as expected we've output the string
breakfast
that's because we explicitly returned
from the method on line two